American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Native American Languages. 1882-1958 Mss.497.3.B63c
American Philosophical Society
- Athapaskan
  - Comparative Na-Dene dictionary, n.d.; AMs, 4 vol. (ca. 500p. each); Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Volumes 1, 3, and 4 are comparative Na-Dene with provision for various Athapascan languages and dialects, Haida, and Tlingit. Volume 2 is comparative Sino-Tibetan-Na-Dene with provision for entries in Sino-Tibetan languages, Athapascan, Haida, and Tlingit. Most pages in all volumes have only a few entries.
    Freeman and Smith 4115
- Atsugewi
  - Parallel Achumawi and Atsugewi texts, TMs, 11p.; Freeland, L. S., (Lucy Shepard), 1890-1972
    Freeman and Smith 4118
    Cf: No. 433
  - The Atsugewi language, 1929; TMs, 71L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Grammar intended for comparison with the author's study of "the Achumawi language." Similar also to their grammar of Shasta. Based on field work sponsored by the American Council of Learned Societies.
    Freeman and Smith 433
    Cf. de Angulo, and Freeland (1930) and No. 30 (H1c.1).
  - Conversational text in Atsugewi, n.d.; TMs, 19p.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Includes: English sentences; Atsugewi equivalents; literal English translations; some grammatical notes; references to the Atsugewi grammar (cf: No. 433) of which it seems to have been a part originally.
    Freeman and Smith 4117
  - Mythological text in Atsugewi, 1929; TMs, 14L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Text with interlinear translation and grammatical notes. Originally part of No. 433.
    Freeman and Smith 432
- Aztec
  - Das Leben im alten Mexico, 1933?; TMs, 17L.; Lange, Gertrud, 1879-
    In German. Discussion of Aztec culture before the Conquest: political organization, society, religion and thought.
    Freeman and Smith 437
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 3
- Bella Bella
  - Bella Bella notes, 1923; TMs and AMs, 175p., 46L., 2 notebooks; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Folkloristic texts in English; ethnographic texts; comments. Images include crayon drawings of masks. Also carbon copy of typescript.
    Freeman and Smith 448
    Cf. Boas (1928(1); No. 30(Wlb.3 and Wlb.5)
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 1
    Drawings.
    - Kwaknma: small owl, 1923
    - Peqis, 1923
  - Salish texts, 1923; TMs and AMs (mostly Cy), 243L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942, et al.
    Primarily Bella Bella texts, in English; c.c. of tales collected by Boas in 1923. Miscellaneous texts; discussion of Coeur d'Alene ethnography. Images include an illustration of a totem figure.
    Freeman and Smith 452
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 2-3
    Illustrations.
  - Bella Bella lexicon, n.d.; Slip file, ca.2,000 slips; Unidentified
    Freeman and Smith 446
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 22
  - Bella Bella lexicon, ca.1930; Slip file, ca.173 slips; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Stem list with illustrative words; part of a larger work (includes A, Y, E, O, stems only).
    Freeman and Smith 447
  - Bella Bella texts, word lists and paradigms, ca. 1925; AMs, 3 ntoebooks; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Texts, grammatical materials, notes in shorthand, annotations. Field notes from various informants. Loose sheets enclosed after 1925.
    Freeman and Smith 449
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 51
  - Bella Bella suffix list, n.d.; AMs, 322L., 5 slips; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Preliminary organization of morphological treatment; heavily exemplifed suffix list. On reverse side are ethnological materials: Land of the Dead (the Sbetetda's ceremony and the conception of the Land of the Dead); the idea of fertilization in the culture of the Pueblo Indians; Hopi Sky-Father and Sky-Mother. In notebooks; notes added after 1925. Some offset printed sheets, pp. 1-171 of Boas (1928a).
    Freeman and Smith 450
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 24
  - Bella Bella texts, n.d.; AMs and TMs, 159L., 93 slips; Hunt, George
    Rough text material with interlinear translations, some in English only. Ethnologic materials. Bella Bella suffixes on slips. Letter from George Hunt to Boas, Feb. 21, 1929.
    Freeman and Smith 451
    Cf. Boas (1928a).
- Bella Coola
  - Bella Coola notes, n.d.; AMs, 81L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Working notes with page references to other documents, not identified.
    Freeman and Smith 453
  - Bella Coola grammatical summaries, 1937; TMs, 18L.; Newman, Stanley S.
    Summaries of phonetic pattern, pronominal schemas, local suffixes, third person references, formation of diminutives, Bella Coola suffixes. Covering letter from Newman to Franz Boas, May 24, 1937.
    Freeman and Smith 455
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 19
- Biloxi
  - Biloxi words, 1934; AMs, 3L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Vocabulary with English equivalents.
    Freeman and Smith 463
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 28
- Blackfoot
  - Blackfoot vocabulary, 1916; AMs, 1L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Compares Blackfoot numerals 1-10 with Kutenai and Flathead.
    Freeman and Smith 465
- Caingang
  - The Kaingang language, 1936; TMs Cy, 46L.; Henry, Jules
    Grammatical sketch, including morphology and grammatical categories. Based upon field work at Santa Catarina, Brazil, 1932-1934.
    Freeman and Smith 498
    Cf. Henry (1935)
- Carrier
  - Carrier notes (Hagwilgate), 1921; AMs, 7L.; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
    Verb paradigms. Informant, Donald Grey.
    Freeman and Smith 502
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 13
  - Notes on various Athabaskan languages, n.d.; 1910?; AMs, 12p.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Carrier vocabulary, Stuwix notes, Suwal vocabulary. Some of these materials used by Franz Boas in his article on Nicola Valley Athapascans (1924).
    Freeman and Smith 505
    Cf. Boas (1924).
- Catawba
  - Catawba lexicon, ca.1935; Slip file, ca.1,000 slips; Susman, Amelia L.
    Partial list, organized by stems. Based on Speck (1934).
    Freeman and Smith 550
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.5, reel 1
  - Catawba field notes, 1937; AMs, 1 ntoebook; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Texts, word lists, paradigms, a Catawba "letter to Speck," minimal parts. Two pages of Alaskan Eskimo.Donor, Morris Swadesh, 1950.
    Freeman and Smith 551
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 53
  - Catawba vocabulary, 1939; Slip file, ca.1,300 slips; Unidentified
    Based on Speck (1934) and on unpublished materials. No apparent order.
    Freeman and Smith 546
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 27
- Cayuse
  - Cayuse interlinear texts, 1930; AMs, 3 notebooks; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Notes; texts with interlinear translations. Nez Perce, language as used by Cayuse Indians of Oregon.
    Freeman and Smith 567
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 48
  - Cayuse lexical file, 1930; Slip file, ca.800 slips; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Cayuse forms with English equivalents, arranged alphabetically by Cayuse. One section, "Wai'letpu Ethnology," concerns use of Cayuse dialect by Walowa and Wallawalla.
    Freeman and Smith 568
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 20
- Central America
  - Intrusion de los idiomas centroamericanos en el America del Sur, 1938; TMs, 20L.; Loukotka, Cestmir
    In Spanish. Comparative study of loans from Central American languages into those of South America; vocabulary of 72 items. Discusses frequency of appearance of related forms in this vocabulary. Prepared for publication, but unprinted.
    Freeman and Smith 584
- Chatino
  - Brevisimas notas sobre el idioma Chatino para el uso de los textos, n.d.; AMs, ca. 30p.; Angulo, Jaime de
    General note
    MICROFILM 372
    In Spanish. Primarily concerned with an analysis of verbs; some discussion of noun declension.
    Freeman and Smith 4160
- Chehalis
  - Chehalis folklore, 1927; TMs Cy, 145p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Folklore and ethnography based on Boas' field notes in No. 589.
    Freeman and Smith 587
    Cf. Boas (1935)
  - Chehalis myths, 1927-1935; TMs, 239p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    56 texts in English, including some variants and additions. Explanatory table of contents has reference numbers to the original manuscript notes, No. 589.
    Freeman and Smith 586
    Printed, 2 pages of text only, Boas (1935)
    Donor, Ruth Benedict, 1946, ed, by E. Aginsky (?).
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 4
  - Comparison of Puyallup and Chehalis, 1935; TMs, 19L.; Aginsky, Ethel Gertrude, 1910-
    Phonology, verbs, pronouns, nouns, articles, reduplication, affixing, numerals, grammatical processes.
    Freeman and Smith 588
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 16
  - Lower Chehalis vocabulary and text, ca.1890; AMs, 13L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Text and vocabulary copied from MS. of Myron Eells in the Bureau of American Ethnology (1882), later corrected by Boas in pencil, probably in the field.
    Freeman and Smith 593
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 18
  - Chehalis field notes, 1927; AMs, 14 notebooks; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Upper Chehalis dialect, Oakville, Washington. Notebooks 1-14, vocabulary, paradigms, and texts with interlinear translation. Also, a copy prepared by Ethel Aginsky (ca. 1935), complete for texts, but not for other notes.
    Freeman and Smith 589
    Cf. No. 586 for typescript.
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 49
  - Chehalis lexical file, 1897; 1927-1935; Slip file, ca. 8,000 slips; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Words derived from Boas' notes in No. 589, pp. 145-291. Pt. 1, slips partly classified into categories, e.g., prefixes, diminutives; slips arranged alphabetically by English (prepared by Boas). Pt. 2, slips not yet filed, partly classified and analyzed by Morris Swadesh, 1950 (prepared by Ethel C. Aginsky).
    Freeman and Smith 590
  - Chehalis lexicon, ca.1935; AMs, 845L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Each sheet is for a given stem (or morpheme), listing examples of 845 Chehalis forms. Based on Boas' field notes, No. 589.
    Freeman and Smith 591
  - Chehalis materials, 1927; 1934-1936; AMs, 440L., 5 slips; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Texts copied from Boas' field notes (1927), No. 589; collected forms for paradigms and other grammatical formulations: a Stem list, alphabetically arranged by the Chehalis; lists of nouns, verbs, and suffixes, alphabetically arranged by the English. Includes copy of noun, verb, and suffix lists; typed c.c. of noun and verb lists.
    Freeman and Smith 594
  - Chehalis field notes, 1882; AMs, 1 notebook; Eels, Myron, 1843-1907, and Franz Boas, 1858-1942
    Words recorded in blank forms in Powell (1877) in 1882. Entries made by Boas at later date.
    Freeman and Smith 595
    Cf. No. 593.
  - Chehalis texts, ca.1890; AMs, 12L and 2p.; Eels, Myron, 1843-1907, and Franz Boas, 1858-1942
    Texts obtained by Eells and by Boas. 5p. have interlinear translation made by Boas in 1890.
    Freeman and Smith 596
  - Chehalis vocabulary, 1934; TMs Cy, 79L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    3 lists: verbs, English-Chehalis, alphabetical by English (ca. 550 forms); nouns, English-Chehalis, alphabetical by English (ca. 450 forms); Chehalis-English word list, alphabetical by Chehalis (ca. 1,100 forms). All copied from materials in No. 594.
    Freeman and Smith 592
- Cherokee
  - Ethiopic and Cherokee syllabaries -- a case of parallelism, TMs, 8L.; Olbrechts, Frans M., 1899-1958
    A formal paper with MS. corrections. The author finds the syllabaries similar in principle, but different in intent; the Ethiopic is a complication of the Minaeo-Sabaean, while the Cherokee is an attempt at simplification. Phonetic equivalences of the two syllabaries are arranged tabularly at the end.
    Freeman and Smith 682
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 7
  - Cherokee materials gathered on the Cherokee reservation at Cherokee, N.C., 1951-1952; AMS and TMs, ca. 4500 cards, 350 slips, 1024L.; Reyburn, William D.
    Three parts: (1) cards filed according to morpheme classes; (2) table of contents, notes for grammatical analysis; (3) phonological materials; ethnographic and other texts (folkloristic; biographic, etc.); series of controlled utterances to illustrate morpheme classes; transcription and translation of recorded reels.
    Freeman and Smith 685
    Cf. Reyburn (1953); and No. 884.
    Donor, William D. Reyburn, grantee, 1952.
    Microfilmed as: Film 685
  - Cherokee materials, 1941-1946; TMs and AMs, 820L., 575 slips, 59 phonograph discs; Harris, Zellig S., (Zellig Sabbettai), 1909-
    Contains grammatical word lists and utterances; skeletal grammar; verb suffix notes; phonological materials; morphological notes; texts (some in syllabary); ethnographical texts; autobiographical texts; utterances; "Gourds and ants"; miscellaneous.
    Freeman and Smith 661
    Mentioned in Reyburn (1953), 172; c.f. Harris and Bender (1946) for use of phonological materials.
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 10-11
- Cheyenne
  - Cheyenne Material, 1948-1949; TMs and AMs, 30 notebooks (344L.); Croft, Kenneth
    3 parts.
    Typed and MS material in folders; noun paradigms, syllable and clusters; modes; instrumentals; affixes; prefixes and suffixes; bases; miscellaneous.
    Notebooks with inserts; north Cheyenne lexical lists, phrases, and text.
    24 notebooks with inserts; south Cheyenne lexical lists, phrases, paradigms, texts.
    Freeman and Smith 693
    Donor, Kenneth Croft, grantee, 1949
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 37-39
- Chichimeca
  - Chichimeco texts, 1930; TMs and AMs, 419L; Angulo, Jaime de
    In Chichimeco and English. 11 folkloristic texts with literal and, free translations.
    Freeman and Smith 695
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 6-7
- Chilula
  - Chilula field notes (Redwood Creek), 1902-1907; AMs, 5 notebooks; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928
    Includes lexical items, texts, translated and untranslated; text and narration on geographical features, materialculture. 1 Kato item included. Used by Goddard for his Chilula studies.
    Freeman and Smith 706
    Cf. Goddard (1914).
    Donor, A. L. Kroeber, for the Department of Anthropology, University of California, 1948.
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 45
  - Chilula field notes, 1906-1907; AMs, 4 notebooks; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928
    Data on village site, material culture, Indian encounter near Fort Seward, text. Texts with interlinear translations. Collected from Bald Hills.
    Freeman and Smith 705
    Printed (texts from 2 notebooks -- excepting those of Molasses), Goddard (1914):289-295.
    Donor, A. L. Kroeber, for the Department of Anthropology, University of California, 1946.
- Chimakum
  - Chemakum materials, 1890; Slip file, ca.1,500 slips; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Includes ca. 100 slips in several small groups, some dealing with Quileute-Chemakum material. Remainder of lexical items organized alphabetically by Chemakum.
    Freeman and Smith 709
    Donor, Department of Anthropology, University of Chicago, 1950.
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 29
  - Chemakum lexicon compared with Quileute, 1952; AMs with AMs additions, 30L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Freeman and Smith 711
    Printed, Swadesh (1955).
  - Chemakum vocabulary, 1853?; TMs, 5L.; Gibbs, George
    Obtained from woman named Jule, slave and mistress of King George, a Clallem chief. English orthography with accents marked. Parts of body, household objects, material objects, animals, adverbs, verbs.
    Freeman and Smith 710
  - Notes on the relations between Chemakum and Quileute; ed. by E. Sapir and M. Swadesh, 1930?-1953; TMs with AMs additions, 10L.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Sapir's comments in black pencil; Swadesh's comments in red. Page 10 gives phonetic system.
    Freeman and Smith 708
    Printed, Andrade et al. (1953a).
    Donor, Norman A. McQuown through Morris Swadesh, 1953
  - Chemakum vocabulary, 1928; AMs, 1 notebook (14p.); Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    English words and sentences with Chemakum equivalent; incomplete. Attempt to verify use of informant, Louise Webster, by Franz Boas at an earlier date.
    Freeman and Smith 707
    Donor, Norman A. McQuown, 1954.
- Chimariko
  - Chimariko notes, 1927; AMs, 1 notebook; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Chimariko forms arranged (in part) alphabetically by English equivalents.
    Freeman and Smith 713
- Chinantec
  - Chinantec text: El perrito de Teotitlan, 1922; AMs Cy, 10L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    In Chinantec-Spanish. Printed, with different orthograplly and English translation, de Angulo and Freeland (1935).
    Freeman and Smith 716
  - Chinantec text: Cuento del pescador, 1922; AMs Cy, 13L. Will illus.; Angulo, Jaime de
    In Chinantec-Spanish and English. Versions in both Yolox and Yetla dialects.
    Freeman and Smith 715
  - Chinantec vocabulary, 1940; AMs and AMs Cy, 4L.; McQuown, Norman A.
    In Spanish-Chinantec, 64 items in Yoloks dialect.
    Freeman and Smith 717
- Chinook
  - Miscellaneous notes on Chinookan languages, 1891-1892; AMs, 6L. and 1L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Wasko vocabulary of 6p., apparently based on Jeremiah Curtin's visit to Warm Springs, Oregon, 1891. A text in an unidentified language and fragmentary slips of Chinook-Kathlamet comparisons.
    Freeman and Smith 725
    Cf. Sapir (1909).
  - List of Chinook morphemes, n.d.; TMs Cy, 15L.; Unidentified
    Detailed list of morphemes. Many forms have criticism and occasional comparative notes on Chinook-Wishram made by Edward Sapir.
    Freeman and Smith 727
  - Chinook lexicon, 1890-1894?; Card file, ca. 900 cards and 16L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Reference numbers probably to field notes. One group labeled "Kwakiutl-to be corrected." Together with No. 722, gives greater lexical information than published works.
    Freeman and Smith 721
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.6, reel 2
  - Chinook lexicon, 1897; Card and slip file, ca. 900 cards and ca. 4,200 slips; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Generally organized by grammatical categories. Reference numbers apparently to field notes.
    Freeman and Smith 722
  - Field notes on Chinookan and Salishan languages and Gitamat [Kwakiutl], Molala [Sahaptian] and Masset [Haida], 1890; AMs, 4 notebooks; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Contents list; texts and vocabularies; shorthand ethnographic notes. Notebooks 1 and 2: Chinook, Wasko, Tlackamas, Kathlamet texts and vocabularies; Clatsop vocabulary. Notebook 3: shorthand notes on Salish tribes; ethnographic shorthand notes on Lower Fraser, Bella Coola, Puyallup; vocabularies for Gitamat, Bella Coola, Chemakum, Puyallup. Notebook 4: shorthand ethnographic notes for Clatsop, Kathlamet, Lower Chehalis, Lower Frazer; vocabularies for Nehalim, Kathlamet, Clatsop, Lower Chehalis, Chinook, Molale, Masset, I,ower Frazer.
    Freeman and Smith 723
  - Field notes on Tillamook and Chinookan dialects, 1890; AMs, 2 notebooks (part in shorthand); Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Notes gathered in 1890. Vocabularies and texts with interlinear translation. Ethnographic notes in shorthand. Table of contents with notebooks. Tillamook, Nehelim, Siletz, Chinookan, Wasko, Tlakamas, Tlatsop, Chinook. Physical notes on Songish skulls, probably collected 1888 or 1889.
    Freeman and Smith 724
- Chinook Jargon
  - Indian legends of the North Pacific coast of North America, 1974; TMs Cy, 600p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Legends in English from the German translation of Chinook Jargon, Kwakiutl, Tsimshian, and Shuswap. Translated by Dietrich Bertz from the original edition (cf: Boas 1895). Permission necessary for reproduction.
    Freeman and Smith 4174
    Donor, British Columbia Indian Language Project, Jan. 1975
- Chitimacha
  - Chitimacha dictionary file, 1950; AMs and TMs slips, ca.4,000 slips; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Lexical file, arranged alphabetically by Chitimacha.
    Freeman and Smith 730
    Donor, Morris Swadesh, 1951.
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 15
  - Chitimacha-English dictionary, 1950; TMs, 89L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Vocabulary alphabetically arranged by the Chitimacha. A duplicate of vocabulary in No. 735 compiled in 1939, based on texts from 1931.
    Freeman and Smith 731
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 5
  - Field notes on Chitimacha, 1930-1934; AMs, 16 notebooks; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Includes texts, vocabulary, phonetics, morphological notes. Notebooks 1,2,3,4,7,10,13, 15, are texts; notebooks 3,5,6,8, contain verb stem materials (cf. slip file, No. 733); notebooks 5,6,8, contain adjective stem materials; notebooks 1,2,9,12, vocabulary; notebook 14, phonetics; notebook 11, morphological notes; notebook 16, miscellaneous; notebook 15 includes Swanton vocabulary of Chitimacha and a genealogy.
    Freeman and Smith 735
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 35-36
  - Chitimacha paradigmatic tables, 1934; Slip file, ca.1,00 slips; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Slips show inflections of verbs, based on No. 735, notebooks 3, 5, 6, 8.
    Freeman and Smith 733
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 6
  - Chitimacha grammar, texts, and vocabulary, 1939; TMs Cy, AMs additions, 606L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Grammar, texts, free translations; vocabulary. Earlier versions of the texts are in Nos. 734 and 731. Vocabulary also in No. 731. Copy 2 of same, lacking pp. 189-170 of grammar.
    Freeman and Smith 732
    Donor, Morris Swadesh, 1953
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 8-9
  - Earlier copies of Chitimacha texts, 1935; TMs part Cy, 851L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Earlier versions of texts in No. 732 with translations; duplicate copies and translations in second part (including grammatical analysis of one text in duplicate). Subject matter of texts is ethnographic (material culture), ethnohistoric, folkloristic, white-Indian-Negro relations.
    Freeman and Smith 734
- Chiwere
  - Materials for a study of the Iowa Indian language, AMs, ca. 1,000L., ca. 4,000 cards, ca. 75 bluebooks of 4L. each, several photographs.; Marsh, Gordon H., comp.
    Cards are in three subdivided sections: parts of speech (containing cognates from Osage, Dakota, Santee, Teton, Ponca, Kansa, and Winnebago); English-Iowa; Iowa-English. Also included: Iowa texts with interlinear English translations; manuscript grammar of Ponca based on material in Dorsey (1890, 1891); gramC: matical notes on Winnebago taken from Lipkin (1945). Images include photographs, sections numbered 7, 19, of portraits, group and individual, with some native attire, dated 1936.
    Freeman and Smith 4178, 4232
    Donor, compiler (now Rev. Priestmonk Innocent), Aug. 1971
- Chocho
  - Chocho text, 1922; AMs Cy, 47L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    Grammatical sketch and text, Cuento del gerrito.... Includes tones, verbs, verb lists, and paradigms. Based on 1922 field work at Nativitas, Coixtlahuaca D., Oaxaca.
    Freeman and Smith 737
    Printed, text only, with different orthography and English translation, de Angulo and Freeland (1935).
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 7
- Chontal
  - Chontal text, 1922; AMs Cy, 24L.; Angulo, Jaime de
    In Chontal-Spanish and English. Grammatical sketch, 11 phrases with notes, and text, El Cuento del Perrito, obtained from pueblo of Tequisistlan.
    Freeman and Smith 745
    Cf. printed reference to grammatical study in de Angulo (1925):97.
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 12
- Clackamas
  - Clackamas vocabulary (?), 1920; AMs, 2L.; Unidentified
    Brief list, arranged alphabetically by English, letters A-D only.
    Freeman and Smith 752
    Microfilmed as: Film 752, reel 14
  - Kinship terms in Upper Chinook (Clackamas), n.d.; Slip file, ca.65 slips; Jacobs, Melville, 1902-1971
    Freeman and Smith 753
- Clallam
  - Clallam and Songish vocabularies, 1888; AMs, 43 L., 20p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Contains a copy of George Gibbs (1863), Clallam vocabulary. Comparisons of Lkungen with other languages. English-Lkungen vocabulary, alphabetical by English. Numbers refer to comparative Salish vocabularies. Miscellaneous Lkungen sentences. Also, Lkungen names, Songish vocabularies.
    Freeman and Smith 755
  - Clallam notes, 1917; AMs, 16L., 6p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942